Bailey-Ann Slaughter

1300 N. Walnut St., Apt. 7, 47404 | (812) 344-0514 | baislaug@indiana.edu

Summary

Aspiring front runner in software development with over two years of active involvement in computational physics research and a passion for innovative contribution. Seeking opportunities, in the form of internships, to work alongside pioneering minds and develop skills instrumental to a prosperous future in an exponentially-growing field.

Technical Skills

PROGRAMMING:

Python, Scheme/Racket, HTML, CSS, PHP

SOFTWARE:

Visual Studio IDE, Adobe Creative Suite 6, MS Office, Eclipse IDE

SYSTEMS:

Linux (Ubuntu), UNIX, Windows (all), Macintosh OS X (basic)

Professional Experience

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE | CENTER FOR EXPLORATION OF ENERGY AND MATTER | APRIL 2012 - PRESENT

- · Prototype high voltage electrodes viable to use in an experiment searching for the electric dipole moment of the neutron.
- Design and implement data-acquisition programs in Matlab for liquid helium cryostats linked to cryogenic temperature controllers and LabView.
- · Constructed and tested components used in a magneto-gravitational potential well currently in use at Los Alamos National Laboratory in an experiment to measure the beta-decay rate of ultracold neutrons (UCN).
- · Constructed a neutron beam chopper using an Arduino stepper motor, Aluminum chassis, and Gadolinium-coated disc; controlled remotely via Matlab Simulink and Arduino libraries.

UNDERGRADUATE INSTRUCTOR, PYTHON | INDIANA UNIVERSITY | JANUARY 2014 - PRESENT

- · Lead weekly laboratory section clarifying and demonstrating fundamental programming constructs in Python, modular programming, and general problem-solving techniques.
- · Responsible for grading weekly assignments submitted by students in the lab section in a timely manner and offering constructive feedback based on individual performance.

SERGEANT, ARABIC CRYPTOLOGIC LINGUIST | INDIANA NATIONAL GUARD | JULY 2007 - PRESENT

- · Achieved one of the highest scores on the Defense Language Aptitude Battery in the state of Indiana.
- · Awarded 5 Army Achievement Medals, 2 Reserve Component Achievement Medals, Military Outstanding Volunteer Service Medal, and two Certificates of Achievement since initial entry.

PEER TUTOR, PYTHON | INDIANA UNIVERSITY | SEPTEMBER 2013 - DECEMBER 2013

 $\cdot\,$ Provide concise interpretation and clarification of course material

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | EXPECTED MAY 2015 | INDIANA UNIVERSITY

- · Computer Science, Specialization in Programming Languages
- · Minor in Physics

ASSOCIATE OF ARTS DEGREE | NOVEMEBER 2011 | DEFENSE LANGUAGE INSTITUTE

- $\cdot\,$ Graduated with Honors for exceeding course standard on the Final Exam
- · Final GPA: 3.6